本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:aimie king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
The path splits.
分かれ道
どっちに行く
Which one do we take?
面倒くせーから　二手に分かれようぜ
Let's take the lazy way and split up.
わかりました
Very well!
では　自分と天間殿はこちらを参ります
Tenma-dono and I will take this way.
さー　参りましょう　天間殿
Let's go, Tenma-dono.
W-Wait...
ちょ　ちょっと
バカ月島
Stupid Tsukishima!
Who Is Righteous!?
Tenma and Justice!
たく
Jeez.
いいのか
You okay with this?
We do not have a choice.
仕方ありません　我らはこちらを
Let's go this way.
Three of the Ten Crucifix Insects are left, right?
十傑蟲　残るは三人よね
あー
Yeah.
最初にやっつけた猿飛佐助に海野六郎　望月六郎　根津甚八
Sarutobi Sasuke, the first one we killed.
Then Unno Rokurou.
Mochidzuki Rokurou.
Nedzu Jinpachi.
あたしが倒した　霧隠才蔵
Also, Kirigakure Saizou, whom I defeated.
And Miyoshi Seikai Nyuudou
and Miyoshi Isa Nyuudou.
それに　三好青海入道に三好伊佐入道
さて　次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
I wonder who'll be next.
楽しみだぜ
I can't wait.
気を引き締めて参りますよ
Let's keep our guard up.
Yukimura-sama...
幸村様
入道二人　打ち取られました
The Nyuudou two have fallen.
残りは四人か
Then four remain?
I'm sorry, sir.
申し訳ございません
まさか　これ以上遅れは取るまいな
Surely, you won't lose any more...
御意
As you wish, sir.
ちょ　月島　そんなに急がなくても
T-Tsukishima, y-you don't have to go so fast.
いえ　そうはいきません
No, I do!
一刻も早く　天守閣に向かわないと
We must reach the top of the
castle with all possible haste!
あー　ちょ
Hey, wait.
Tenma-dono?
天間殿
つ　月島が迷子になるといけないから
I d-don't want you getting lost.
ここか　蟲人
Are you in here, Insect-Men?
L-Loud sounds kind of scare me,
so please keep it down.
大きい音　ちょこっとだけ苦手だから
静かにして
もしやここか
Or maybe here?
間違いない
This is it!
さ　参りましょう　天間殿
Let's go, Tenma-dono.
無理　無理　無理　無理　無理
No! No! No! No!
どこだ　蟲人
Where are you, Insect-men?
No way!
天間殿　もしかしてあなたはあらゆる物を怖がっていらっしゃるのでは
Tenma-dono, are you scared of everything?
い　今だけだよ　そのうちちゃんと大丈夫になるもん
J-Just for now... I'll be fine soon!
なんと　素晴らしいお志です
What? That's splendid thinking!
天間殿のそのお気持ちがあれば
With that thought in mind,
you'll be able to overcome any fear.
きっとどんな苦手も克服できましょう
あ　当たり前だよ
O-Of course.
だって　僕は出来る子だもん
I can do this.
I'll be okay with insects, cramped spaces,
high places or dark spaces...
虫も　狭い所も　高い所も　暗い所も大丈夫になって
てもって　日本一の陰陽師になってさ
And I'll be the best onmyodo in Japan.
For my mother and father.
父様と母様に
天間殿
Tenma-dono...
あ　あのさ
H-Hey...
月島は父様と母様の事　思い出したりする
Do you ever think of your mom and dad?
Of course!
もちろんです
My father invented the
Tsukishima-style of swordsmanship,
月島流剣術の創始者である父上は　我が生涯の目標です
and he's the man I admire most!
あ　あのすごくうるさい人
Oh, that really annoying guy.
母上は　自分を生んですぐに亡くなりました
My mother...
She died soon after I was born.
そっか
I see.
天間殿のご両親はどのような方達ですか
What are your parents like?
僕の父様はね
My father, well...
とっても大きくて　強くて
My father is big and strong.
母様はとっても綺麗で　お裁縫がお上手で
And my mother is really pretty
and good at sewing.
二人共　僕の事をいつも思っててくださるの
And both of them are always thinking of me...
But I've never met them.
でも　会った事無いんだ
What?
なんと
すごく小さい時に離れちゃったから
When I was really little, we were separated.
僕は父様と母様のお顔も本当は
I don't even remember their faces...
Then they must be really looking
forward to meeting you.
では　お二人共さぞや天間殿にお会いできる日を楽しみにしている事でしょう
そうかな
You think so?
そうだよね だって　父様と母様だもんね
You're right...
They're my mother and father, right?
はい
Right!
僕　頑張らないと　出来る子にならなくちゃ
I need to do my best.
I need to be a good kid.
その息です　天間殿
That's right, Tenma-dono!
I'll defeat the Insect-men!
蟲人だって　倒してみせる
Life
ジャスティス
Justice.
俺は 穴山ジャスティス小介だ
My name is Anayama "Justice" Kosuke.
えっと　ジャスティスって何
Uh, what's "justice"?
ジャスティス　それはすなわち正義
Justice is that which is righteous.
我が心に赤々と燃える正義の焔のことなり
The flames of justice burn within me.
入って来い　一乃谷天間
Come inside, Ichinotani Tenma.
ジャスティスを教えてやろう
I shall teach you of justice.
ぼ　僕
M-Me?
天間殿　これは千載一遇のチャンス
Tenma-dono, this is the chance of a lifetime.
天間殿の出来る所を　ズバッと見せつけてやりましょう
Let's show them what you can do!
Uh, really?
え　そ
そ
Really!
Really?
そ　そんなの当然だよ
O-Of course.
あー　言っちゃった
I should have kept my mouth shut!
Then let us have a fair fight.
では　いざ　尋常に勝負
僕は出来る子
I can do this!
急々如律令
Do my bidding!
I'm sure that sound is
Hibachi-neesama and her friends.
あの音はきっと　火鉢姉様達です
Then we should hurry.
こっちも急がねぇとな
はいです
Yes.
月組も負けていられないです
The Moon Group must do its job, too.
Justice!
ジャスティス
為吉
Tamekichi...
Speed
Full-Power Slap Combo!
全力連続つっぱり
末吉
Matsukichi...
Strength
Full-Power Mega-Slap!
全力大つっぱり
なんと
What?
式神が前より格段にパワーアップしている
Your shikigami are much more
powerful than last time.
早さの為吉で相手を止めて
Tamekichi is the fast one,
so he locks down the enemy...
力の末吉で思いっきり仕留める
And Matsukichi, the strong one, finishes it...
今までよりずっと強く　ずっと頑丈になった末吉と為吉
They're both stronger and tougher than before!
この僕より強い奴なんていない
No one is stronger than I am!
全力つっぱり
Full-Power Slap!
こいつ　やっぱり強い
It's really strong...
でも逃げちゃ駄目だ
But I can't run!
僕は出来る子なんだから
Because I can do this.
ジャスティス
Justice!
天間殿
Tenma-dono!
なんと
What?
一ジャスティス
One justice.
Justice is power.
ジャスティスとはすなわち力
あ　あの
U-Um...
Why did you save me?
なんで助けてくれたの
お前にはまだ　死ぬ資格が無い
You don't have the right to die yet.
いざ　尋常に
Now let us fight...
な　なんだ　あの構え
Wh-What is that stance?
勝負
fair and square!
は　早すぎて見えない
H-He's too fast to see!
ジャスティス
Justice!
痛みもまた　ジャスティスへの道
Pain is also a path to justice.
これで　二ジャスティスだ
That makes two justices...
Y-You're making fun of me!
バ　馬鹿にして
I can fight, too!
僕だって
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
まだまだ
I'm not done yet!
末吉
Matsukichi!
どうだ
Well?
What?
なんと
天間殿　一体どれほどの修行を
Tenma-dono, how much have you trained?
今の攻撃はよかった　一乃谷天間
That was an excellent attack, Ichinotani Tenma.
早さも力も先程より増したな
Your speed and power are greater than before.
うむ　このまま頑張れば
Just keep at it...
And you'll be able to die.
死ねるぞ
さ　共にジャスティスへ至る栄光の階段を登ろう
Now, let us ascend the eternal staircase to justice!
The path splits.
分かれ道か
どちらへ行けば
Which way do we go?
こちらだ　山県
This way, Yamagata.
Princess...
姫君
この先だ 遠くない
It's this way.
It isn't far.
なるほど
I understand.
この先に姫君が力を取り戻す何かがあるのか
Something lies ahead that can
restore the princess's power.
一乃谷天間　涙はジャスティスに必要ないぞ
Ichinotani Tenma, there's no
need for tears in justice.
な　泣いてなんか
I'm n-not crying...
嘘をつかぬ事こそ　ジャスティスへの道
Not lying is the path to justice!
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
Stop trying to rely on violence.
すぐに暴力に訴えようとするな
人は　話せば分かり合えるジャスティスだ
Justice says people can understand
one another by speaking.
And my fists are speaking of justice!
そして　俺の拳は
対話ジャスティスだ
ジャスティスは物を散らかさない
Justice doesn't make a mess.
Did you justice-brush your teeth?
歯は　ジャスティスに磨いたか
Did you justice-eat all your veggies?
野菜は残さず　ジャスティス食べているか
きちんとジャスティス挨拶はしているか
Do you greet people properly with justice?
早寝早起き早ジャスティス
Early to bed, early to rise, makes a man justice!
どうやらお前はジャスティスがまったく分かってないらしいな
It seems you understand nothing of justice...
一乃谷天間　お前にジャスティスの三つの真髄を解いてやろう
Ichinotani Tenma, I shall tell you
the three core tenants of justice.
まずは　一つ目
First up.
ジャスティスは強くならねばならぬ
Justice must be strong.
心技体
Heart, technique and body.
いずれにあっても　強くなければジャスティスとは言えん
All of them must be strong for justice.
What?
何と　これではなぶっているだけではないか
You're just beating him up!
そそそそそそして　二つ目
And the second!
月島
Tsukishima!
Abandon your comrades.
捨てよ　仲間を
And abandon your family.
そして　捨てよ　家族を
家族
Family...
一乃谷天間　お前は父母に会うために蟲奉行所に入ったのだったなぁ
Ichinotani Tenma, did you not
join the Insect Magistrate's
in order to meet your parents?
どうしてそれを
How did you know?
Because I've always watched you.
見ていたからだ　ずっとお前を
そして分かった
And I realized you,
仲間に頼り　式神に頼り　家族に頼るお前こそ
who rely on your friends,
your shikigami and family,
俺が真にジャスティスを分からせるべき相手であるということが
are the boy I must instruct in the ways of justice.
よいか　そのようなものに頼っていては
Listen...
As long as you lean on those things,
真のジャスティスには到達できん
you can never attain true justice.
Whatever binds you will keep you
from the path of justice!
あらゆる柵は　ジャスティスの妨げにすぎん
しかるのち全ての希望を捨てよう
And then, you throw away all hope.
天間
Tenma?
バツです　火鉢殿
That's wrong, Hibachi-dono.
心配している暇はありません
We have no time for worry.
先を急ぎますよ
Let's hurry.
分かってるわよ　あの子なら絶対大丈夫
I know that.
He'll be fine.
Tenma...
天間
84 justices.
八十四ジャスティス
85 justices.
八十五ジャスティス
八十六ジャスティス
86 justices.
最後のは効いただろう
That last one hurt, didn't it?
うむ　特別に三ジャスティスでカウントしてやろう
I'll count it as three.
これで八十九ジャスティスだ
That makes 89 justices.
素晴らしい　今までの最高記録は八十六ジャスティスだった
Splendid.
My previous high score was 86 justices...
記録更新だ　一乃谷天間
A new record!
Ichinotani Tenma, you and I will
reach new heights of justice.
お前となら　新たなるジャスティスの高みを目指すことができそうだ
お互い頑張ろう
Let's both do our best...
Now, where was I?
さて　どこまで話したかな
あ　そうだ　ジャスティスの三つの心得だったな
Oh, that's it.
The three tenants of justice, right?
三つ目は至極簡単だ
The third is very simple.
ジャスティスイコール俺だ
I am justice!
さぁ　一乃谷天間
Well, Ichinotani Tenma, let's finish this.
最後の仕上げと行こう
これをもって　俺とお前のジャスティスは完成する
This will complete your justice through me.
負けを認めよ　そして言え
Admit your defeat,
and say that I am the one true justice!
俺が唯一無二のジャスティスだと
そうすれば　お前は死ねる
If you do, you can die.
聞こえる
I can hear it.
The sound of the waves.
波の音
The well is just ahead.
井戸はやはりこの先だな
We'll be there soon.
もうすぐ着く
そして　わらわは
And then, I...
Now, let's finish this.
さ　仕舞いにしよう
Say it and you can end this.
言え　そして楽になるがよい
I... I...
ぼ　僕は
Stop!
だめです
言ってはだめです　天間殿
Don't say it, Tenma-dono...
You want to show your parents how
hard you're trying, don't you?
ご両親に頑張っている姿を　見せるんでしょう
I'm cold.
寒っ
Tenma, your parents spent three
days and nights making these.
天間　そなたの両親が三日三晩かけて作られたものです
My mother and father...
父様と母様　か
Tenma, fulfill your duty as soon as you can.
天間　早くお務めを果たしなさい
Your parents wanted to see you
after you'd grown strong.
あなたの親も　強くなったあなたに会いたがっていましたよ
My father is big and strong...
父様はとても大きくて　強くて
And my mother is really pretty
and good at sewing.
母様はとても綺麗で　お裁縫がお上手で
And both of them are always...
Always thinking of me!
二人とも僕のことをいつも　いつも思ってて
And I'm going to see them!
僕は父様母様に会うんだ
You still don't understand?
まだ分からぬか
As long as you rely on those things,
you can never win!
そのようなものに頼っている　お前に勝機などない
Whenever I think of my mother and father,
父様母様のことを考えると　ここが熱くなるんだ
my heart feels warm...
It gives me power...
力が湧いてくるんだ
That's why I won't lose!
だから
僕は　負けない
Tamekichi!
為吉
Matsukichi!
末吉
Limiter Off! Transform!
リミッターをトランスフォーム
Combine!
合体
Great Yokodzuna Version!
大横綱バージョン
What?
何と
Target: Lock On.
ターゲット　ロックオン
Auto-killer Mode!
オートキラーモード
Interesting.
面白い
True justice lies in defeating absolute
evil with absolute power.
絶対的な悪を　絶対的な力で打ち破ってこそ
真のジャスティス
Roar, my justice!
燃えろ　俺のジャスティス
No, he's shedding his skin!
いけない　脱皮する
見せてやろう　これこそ俺の
I'll show you! This is my...
フルパワー　パーク
Full-Power Attack!
...true justice!
真のジャスティ
I never knew...
I never knew such justice existed!
まさか
まさかこんなジャスティスがあったとは
I can do it...
僕はできる…子
Huh? I...
あれ　僕
よく頑張りましたね　天間
Well done, Tenma.
は　は　母様
M-Mother?
よし　強くなったな　天間
You've grown strong, Tenma.
F-Father...
ち　ち　父様
We're very proud of you.
お前は私達の誇りだよ
We knew you could do it.
分かっていましたよ
天間ができる子だって
おー　気がつかれましたか　天間殿
You're awake, Tenma-dono?
Tsukishima?
月島
素晴らしい攻撃でしたね
That was a wonderful attack!
You really are strong!
やはり天間殿は　お強い
T-Tenma-dono?
天　天間殿
I'll walk!
歩く
Father... Mother...
父様　母様　もう少しだけ待っていてください
Just wait a little longer.
I'll get stronger! So I can do even more!
僕はもっと強く　もっとできる子になります
So I can see you as soon as possible!
一日も早く　お二人にお会いするために
We've been waiting for you.
待っていましたよ
Ten Crucifix Insects
Kakei Juuzou
Yuri Kamanosuke
This blizzard is too cold.
Next Time
この吹雪寒すぎます
It's your time to shine, Hibachi-dono.
火鉢殿の出番です
To melt the snow with a bomb, right?
爆弾で雪を融かすのね
いいえ　ご自慢の褌で乾布摩擦を
No, use your loincloth to
start a fire with friction!
ごしごし　じゃないわ
Rub rub... Wait, no!
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行「我が生涯で一番のお務め」
My Life's Greatest Task.
My Life's Greatest Task